



MD Khairul Islam

Date of birth: 19 Oct 1997 | **Nationality:** Bangladeshi | **Gender:** Male |

(+880) 1515267153 | khairul4166@gmail.com | http://khairul-islam.com/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/khairul-islam-61859517b/

House No: 169, New Palton Line, Azimpur, 1205, Dhaka, Bangladesh

About me:

I am MD Khairul Islam. I am working as an Android Developer at Easital Technologies Limited, Dhaka, Bangladesh. I completed Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering from Daffodil International University, Dhaka-Bangladesh. I have competency in Android Application Development both Java and Kotlin Language and also have expertness in Data mining and Machine Learning.

WORK EXPERIENCE

17 MAY 2021 - CURRENT - Dhaka, Bangladesh

ANDROID APPLICATION DEVELOPER – EASITAL TECHNOLOGIES LIMITED

Main activities and responsibilities:

- Collaborate the project with other platform developers.
- Build new feature and upgrade existing feature of assigned projects.
- Fixed bug of the code and design according to UI design pattern.
- Maintain chain of command among the team members.
- Complete the assigned task in the deadline.

Contributed Projects:

- Beeda Super Application (Describe in project section)
- GOGO Ride (Describe in project section)

Learning Outcome:

• Got experience to work in industry level projects.

https://easital.com/

1 JAN 2021 - APR 2021 - Dhaka, Bangladesh

TRAINER - "BITE IN ANDROID WITH KOTLIN" - DAFFODIL INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY COMPUTER & PROGRAMING CLUB

I worked here as a Trainer of Android Application Development Course with "Kotlin" programing language. During my working time I describe all basic and advance topics of android application development. It was a live training course in which i showed every example with real time project. It was a four months long training program.

1 SEP 2020 - 31 DEC 2020 - Dhaka, Bangladesh

TRAINER - "DIVE IN ANDROID" - DAFFODIL INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY COMPUTER & PROGRAMING CLUB

A Comprehensive Android Bootcamp. It is android Application development training program with "Java" programing language. In this bootcamp i tried to teach almost every components of android application development with practical example and end of the course I showed a real life project. It was a four month long training program.

PROJECTS

1 MAY 2021 - CURRENT

Super Application "Beeda"

https://play.google.com/store/apps/developer?id=Beeda+Technology&hl=en&gl=US

This is a part of my job project and it is a USA-based super application in which have almost 25+ services like Taxi, Courier, E-commerce, Food Delivery, Water & Gas supply, etc. This project has 4 application for user, driver, store owner and service provider. We are upgrading and adding new features to this project now. The programming languages of this project for android are Java and Kotlin also PHP-Laravel back end. It will be waiting for launch locally and globally (USA and Jamaica).

1 SEP 2021 - CURRENT

GOGO Ride

This is a part of my job project. It is a Ride sharing application which provide Bike, Taxi and Courier service. It has two application for driver and user. User can easily book for ride and courier service. This application is waiting for Launce in local market in Bangladesh.

1 DEC 2021 - 30 DEC 2021

Weather Forcast Application

https://github.com/Khairul/Weather-App

In this application a user get the weather information his/her nearest area and see the area location in google map. A user also can set the weather alert in this application. This project is build with MVVM(Model-View-View Model) coding architecture pattern and user a public weather API for retrieving the weather data. The project language is "Kotlin"

1 SEP 2020 - 1 DEC 2020

Smart Teaching System

https://github.com/Khairul/Smart-Teaching-System

This is a project in which a student get appointment from teacher. When student apply for appointment then sent a notification to the teacher. When the teacher notified then the teacher can see the details about student. Then the teacher can accept/decline the notification. When the teacher response, the student get a notification with teacher reply. This is the actually main work this apps. I use MVVVM Architecture coding pattern in this project and used Android SQLite Database and Google Firebase Database.

1 JAN 2021 - 1 APR 2021

Find Location

https://github.com/Khairul/My-Ride-App

This an Application in which a user can see the route origin and destination place and also can find the time and distance between two place. User also can find nearest hospital, shopping mall and hospital. Here I use kotlin programing language, Google map SDK, Google map apis, Retrofit, Material Design Components and coroutines.

MedHist

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1UCOlcH5pxUcyPjFAyubxQqszvij1Vp-Y/view

This is an Android app that keeps track of human health. In this app, a user can save his/her medical data (Prescription, Checkup report, Medicine name, Doctor Appointment data, etc.). It is built with the Firebase Real time Database and Java Programing Language.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

1 SEP 2020 - 30 APR 2021

Early Identifying Heart Disease by Prediction Using Data Mining

This a final year thesis of my Undergraduate course and I work here as a team member. In this thesis we analysis the data of heart disease patient and predict the probability of heart disease. We use different types of machine learning algorithms to analysis data.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

1 MAY 2017 – 30 APR 2021 – Daffodil International University, Daffodil Smart City, Ashulia, Dhaka, Bangladesh **BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING –** Daffodil International University

Field(s) of study

- Programming and Problem Solving
- Data Structures & Algorithms
- Data Communication
- Database Management System
- Computer Network
- Software Engineering
- Wireless Programming
- Artificial Intelligence
- Data Mining

Thesis: Early Identifying Heart Disease by Prediction Using Data Mining

3.81 out of 4.00 (95.25 %) | EQF level 6 | higher Education | 148 | https://daffodilvarsity.edu.bd/

1 MAY 2013 - 30 JUN 2015 - EPZ Road, Tomsom bridge, Comilla., Comilla, Bangladesh

HIGHER SECONDARY CERTIFICATE (H.S.C) - Ibn Taimiya College

Field(s) of study

- Mathematics
- Physics
- Chemistry
- Information and Communication Technologies
- English

4.67 out of 5.00 (93.4%) | EQF level 5 | Higher Secondary Level | http://www.eduitsc.com/

1 JAN 2011 – 28 FEB 2013 – Chouddagram, Cumilla, Cumilla, Bangladesh

SECONDARY SCHOOL CERTIFICATE(S.S.C) - Chouddagram H. J. Pilot High School

Field(s) of study

- Physics
- Mathematics
- Chemistry
- Biology
- English

4.94 out of 5.00 (98.8%) | EQF level 4 | Secondary Level

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **BENGALI**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	B1	B2	B2	B2	B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Android Development (Kotlin, Java) | Google tools (Gmail Drive Google forms etc) | Microsoft Office, Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Outlook, Facebook, Google | Team-work oriented | GIT Hub

HONOURS AND AWARDS

10 OCT 2019

Achived First Position - Daffodil International University

DIUTHON (Mobile Application Development Contest), Daffodil ICT Carnival – 2019. The contest held in Daffodil International University at 4th October 2019. It was a day long contest. There was 28+ team and we achieved the first position.

1 SEP 2017

Daffodil International University Schloarship - Daffodil International University

I got scholarship from my department for brilliant academic result in different semesters. This scholarship waived my tuition fee up to 50%

CREATIVE WORKS

12 OCT 2017 - CURRENT

Content Creator in YouTube

I have a YouTube channel named "**Artless Uzzal**" in which I make video tutorial in different topics of Computer Science. Such as Android Application Programing, Kotlin Programing language, Course Tutorial. I make this content in Bangla language for my countries student. Because English content is available in internet and at the beginner level it is very difficult to understand in English. For that reason I start to make this type of content to help the student of my country. https://www.youtube.com/c/ArtlessUzzal

1 MAY 2017 - 30 APR 2021

Class Representative

I had selected CR(Class Representative) in first semester 2017 and continue this job till the end of graduation. During this journey I lead my classmate in different competition, seminar and batch programs. It enhance my leadership and team work skill.